remita.net 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy

## 1.0 Your Privacy Rights

This Privacy Policy describes your privacy rights regarding our collection, use, storage, sharing and protection of your personal information. It applies to the REMITA website and all its applications, services, tools and content regardless of how you access or use them. 

## 2.0 Consent

You accept this Privacy Policy when you sign up for, access, or use our products, services, content, features, technologies or functions offered on our website and all related sites, applications, and services (collectively “Remita services”). This Policy governs the use of Remita by our users unless otherwise agreed through a written contract. We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time by posting a revised version on our website. The revised version will be effective seven (7) days after posting. 

## 3.0 Your Personal Information

When you use Remita Services, we collect information sent to us by your computer, mobile phone, POS or other electronic access devices. The automatically collected information includes but is not limited to data about the pages you access, computer IP address, device ID or unique identifier, device type, geo-location information, computer and connection information, mobile network information, statistics on page views, traffic to and from the sites, referral URL, ad data, and standard web log data. 

We may also collect information you provide us including but not limited to- information on web forms, account update information and correspondence with Remita support services. We also collect information about your transactions and your activities. In addition, we collect your contact information such as- name, address, phone number, email, etc. We also collect your bank account name and numbers and link it up to your Remita account. Information obtained through survey responses, telephone conversations, customer enquiries and other means may also be collected and used by us. 

We may also use information provided by third parties like social media sites and verification agencies. Information about you provided by other sites are not controlled by Remita and we are therefore not liable for how they use it. 

## 4.0 What we do with your personal information

The purpose of our collecting your personal information is to give you an efficient, enjoyable and secure customer experience. We may use your information to: 

4.1 Provide REMITA services and support;  
4.2 Process transactions and send notices about your transactions to requisite parties;  
4.3 Verify your identity;  
4.4 Resolve disputes, collect fees, and troubleshoot problems;  
4.5 Manage risk, or detect, prevent, and/or remediate fraud or other potentially prohibited or illegal activities;  
4.6 Detect, prevent or remediate violations of policies or applicable user agreements;  
4.7 Improve our Services by implementing aggregate customer preferences;  
4.8 Measure performance of Remita Services and improve content, technology and layout;  
4.9 Manage and protect our information technology infrastructure;   
4.10Contact you at any time through your provided telephone number, email address or other contact details;  
4.11Notify you about your account, troubleshoot problems with your account, resolve a dispute, collect fees or monies owed, poll your opinions through surveys or questionnaires, enforce our policy, or as otherwise necessary to service your account, we may contact you through information provided.  

SystemSpecs will not request for your Personal Identification Number (PIN), Account Identification Number (AIN) or Dynamic Authentication Number (DAN) from you. We do not use information that has been made personal to a specific user.

## 5.0 Cookies

Cookies are small files placed on your computer's hard drive that enables the website to identify your computer as you view different pages. Cookies allow websites and applications to store your preferences in order to present contents, options or functions that are specific to you. Like most interactive websites, and online platforms, Remita uses cookies to enable the tracking of your activity for the duration of a session. Our platform uses only encrypted session cookies which are erased either after a predefined timeout period or once the user logs out of the platform and closes the browser. Session cookies do not collect information from the user's computer. They will typically store information in the form of a session identification that does not personally identify the user. 

We do not have access or control over the cookies of our partners, affiliates, and service providers. We are therefore not responsible for their use of cookies.

## 6.0 How we protect your personal information

We store and process your personal information on our computers in Nigeria, Africa and elsewhere in the world where our facilities are located. We protect your information using physical, technical, and administrative security measures to reduce the risks of loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure and alteration. Some of the safeguards we use are firewalls and data encryption, physical access controls to our data centers, and information access authorization controls.

## 7.0 How We Share your information with other Relevant Parties

During your transaction, we may provide the corresponding party with information such as your name, account identification details, contact details, shipping and billing address, or other information needed to promote the integrity and security of the transaction. We may also provide details of unsuccessful transactions. 

We work with third parties, including merchants, to enable them to accept or send payments from or to you, using Remita. In doing so, a third party may share information about you with us, such as your email address or mobile phone number, to inform you that a payment has been sent to you or when you attempt to pay a merchant or third party. We use this information to confirm that you are a Remita customer and that Remita as a payment and collection platform can be enabled. We also validate your status as a Remita customer to third parties on your instruction. 

You accept that your pictures and testimonials on all social media platforms about Remita can be used for limited promotional purposes by SystemSpecs or its agents. This does not include your trademark or copyright protected materials.

Where your employee, as part of the process of application for a service from SystemSpecs or a third party, requires his/her data to be provided in support of such an application to SystemSpecs or a third party, SystemSpecs is obligated to avail such request, upon the employee giving the requisite authorisation as the Data Owner, in the form prescribed by SystemSpecs or the third party. 

From time to time we may send you relevant information such as product updates, new functionalities, tips on how to use the platform and new service offerings.

We may also share your personal information in compliance with local or international regulatory requirements, with fraud prevention and risk management agencies with our service providers or in compliance with a court order. 

## 8.0 Security

We will always hold your information securely. To prevent unauthorized access to your information, we have implemented controls and security safeguards at technical and operational levels. This site uses Secure Sockets Layer/Transport Layer Security (SSL/TLS) to ensure secure transmission of your personal data. You should see the padlock symbol in your URL address bar once you are successfully logged into the platform. The URL address will also start with https:// depicting a secure webpage. SSL applies encryption between two points such as your PC and the connecting server. Any data transmitted during the session will be encrypted before transmission and decrypted at the receiving end. This is to ensure that data cannot be read during transmission.

## 9.0 Data Confidentiality Rights

Client information is regarded as confidential and will not be divulged to any third party except under legal and/or regulatory conditions. You have the right to request for copies of all information we keep on you, provided that you give us reasonable notice of such a request. While SystemSpecs is responsible for safeguarding the information entrusted to us, your role in fulfilling confidentiality duties includes but is not limited to adopting and enforcing appropriate security measures such as non-sharing of passwords and other platform login details.

## 10.0 Links to Other Websites

Certain transaction processing channels may require links to other websites. Please note that SystemSpecs is not responsible for and has no control over third party websites. We do not monitor or review the content of other party's websites which are linked from this website. Opinions expressed or materials appearing on such websites are not necessarily shared or endorsed by us, and SystemSpecs should not be regarded as the publisher of such opinions or materials. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices, or content of any third party sites and we encourage our users to read the privacy statements of these sites. You should evaluate the security and trustworthiness of any other site connected to this site or accessed through this site yourself, before disclosing any personal information to it. SystemSpecs will not accept any responsibility for any loss or damage in whatever manner, howsoever caused, resulting from your disclosure to third parties of personal information.

We reserve the right to modify our Policy at any time and without any prior notice to you. Ensure you check this Policy regularly to stay updated with any amendment and understand how we use your information.
